

# Paul Lehn

Fort Lauderdale, FI 33301

pmlehn@gmail.com
www.PaulLehn.com

(803) 369-5584

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated Mobile Application Developer adept at creating and managing apps and solutions for clients ranging from small startups to The US Government. Interests and skills include mobile application development specializing in IOS, website development, and database management. Successful technology career comprising more than 10 years.

## **SKILLS**

- Training and mentoring
- Application development (Swift, Flutter, CocoaPods/SPM, RESTFUL API integration, XCTests, UIKit, SwiftUI)
- Managing CI/CD pipelines (fastlane, Circle CI, Github Actions)
- Website development (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- Database Management (SQL, MvSQL, Firestore, Parse Server)

- Version-control (GIT, Github, Bitbucket)
- Software/IDEs (Xcode, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, DataGrip, Sourcetree, Postman, Proxyman, Marvel, Figma)
- Spoken Languages: English, Croatian

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

04/2021 to CURRENT

#### Updater | New York, NY

Working with a mid-sized team managing the suite of Updater apps that focus on end-to-end solutions for the moving industry. Major projects include:

<u>Dolly Customer</u> and <u>Dolly Helper</u>

- On-demand moving service.
- Full redesign and refactors of existing code bases.
- Feature development with A/B tested rollouts.
- Built out a robust CI/CD pipeline for the mobile team

#### **HSCGO** (not yet live):

- Greenfield SwiftUI build of the app that will drive all moves of U.S. Armed Forces, Department of Defense (DoD) civilians, and their families.
- Used the latest in the SwiftUI and Combine frameworks to implement a modern, well tested, and future proof codebase
- Implemented over 500 stated requirements by the government involving security, privacy, offline capabilities, and analytics.

## PRINCIPAL APPLICATION DEVELOPER

12/2017 to 04/2021

## Reatro Ventures, LLC. | Boca Raton, FL

Lead developer of mobile applications for Reatro Ventures, working with a close knit team to implement ideas and bring them to life on the app store, with a focus on IOS. Closely involved in the full cycle of app development including: communicating directly with clients, mapping out their ideas, working closely with the design team, wireframing, developing, testing, launching apps in the app store, and releasing updates.

Some examples of apps released:

- Emvite: Emoji based social media
- <u>BodyPeace</u>: Instructional subscription based yoga
- <u>PickleJar</u>: Live performance tipping
- Famclub: Subscription box and chore tracking

#### LEAD IOS DEVELOPER

08/2016 to 12/2017

## MojiLife Inc. | Boca Raton, FL

Managed, implemented, tested, and deployed all versions of a highly complex 3-1 Social Media app. The app combines Social, Professional, and Dating accounts into one clean, easy to use experience.

- Developed complex features such as creating and editing profiles, companies, linking and importing posts from Facebook/Instagram, Tinder-like dating interface, full blown chat, push notifications, etc.
- Integrated with our custom API as well as with Google Places, Maps, Instagram, and Facebook.

## LEAD IOS DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR)

08/2015 to 05/2016

#### Npute Inc. | West Palm Beach, Florida, FL

Developed a high end classifieds IOS app that plugs into the "Listy" network. Users can post new listings of items they wish to sell as well as find items they may be interested in buying.

- Implemented features such as map integration, optional Craigslist feed, custom built and secure Chat.
- The app was built with Swift, using MapKit, custom API, and open source libraries imported via CocoaPods.

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / IOS DEVELOPER

08/2014 to 06/2015

#### Bass Egg Inc. | West Palm Beach, Florida

Developed software for Bass Egg, completing projects as assigned. Some of these projects include:

- Android app designed for tablets used in trade show display booths.
- IOS application to connect with Bass Egg speaker. This Included low level audio manipulation and equalization using CoreAudio and AVPlayer.
- Google program for automating email survey management.
- Installation of security system
- Web app for customizing/purchasing Bass Eggs.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

04/2013 to 06/2013

## Forte Interactive | West Palm Beach, FL

 Developed and Implemented websites, where I received Photoshop files from the design department and converted them into fully functional websites. This involved slicing out individual layers of the documents and using HTML, CSS, and Javascript to position them correctly and make them function exactly as expected.

- Fast paced environment with multiple websites being worked on at once.
   Most websites were for nonprofit organizations.
- Example work: <a href="http://www.myamicimarket.com/">http://www.myamicimarket.com/</a>

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science Palm Beach Atlantic University, West Palm Beach, Florida Honors: 12/2014

- Computer Science Club Treasurer
- Community Service
- Winner of the Palm Beach Atlantic computer game programming contest for 2012

## **High School Diploma**

05/2011

The American International School of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia *IB Diploma (International Baccalaureate), GPA 3.7* Honors:

- Student Government
- Intramural Basketball
- Community Service

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **REFERENCES**

Matt Pappas Boca Raton, Florida
Creative Director at Reatro Ventures, LLC.
(727) 534 5505, matt.pappas@reatro.com
David Taylor West Palm Beach, Florida
Chief Technology Officer at NPute Inc.
(561) 329 5673, wtaylor@npute.com
Craig Henderson Boca Raton, Florida
Chief Technology Officer at Mojilife Inc.
(561) 350 8840

**Dr. Kenneth Pembamotto** West Palm Beach, Florida Dean of Computer Science at Palm Beach Atlantic University (561) 707 2067, kenneth.pembamotto@pba.edu